Lu Qi, Yang Zhenzhong, Zhang Kai.
Lu Qi! Yang Zhenzhong! Zhang Kai!
What beautiful hands.
Tangan yang sangat indah.
I thought
Awalnya mengira
I had time
aku punya waktu.
to wait patiently
bisa pelan-pelan
for you to achieve your dream,
menunggumu mewujudkan impianmu.
but now it seems
Tapi sekarang,
I'm getting impatient.
aku sudah tidak sabar lagi.
Soon,
Sebentar lagi.
Meng Xiaoting
Xiao Ting.
will be the final note
akan menjadi
to fulfill our dream.
untuk mewujudkan impian kita.
From now on,
Kelak di tubuhmu
you can only smell like me,
hanya boleh ada aromaku.
you cannot have
Tidak boleh ada.
any other woman's scent on you.
bau wanita lain.
In this lifetime,
Seumur hidup ini,
you'll never escape me,
kamu tidak akan bisa kabur.
you can only be mine.
Kau hanya bisa menjadi milikku.
I guess in my entire life,
Seumur hidupku,
I'll never find someone who loves
tidak akan menemukan orang
me as much as she does.
orang yang begitu menyukaiku.
There's something wrong with the medicine,
Obatnya bermasalah.
which means
Itu berarti
there's something wrong with Chen Mo.
Chen Mo yang bermasalah.
However,
Tapi,
how can you be sure?
Bagaimana kau yakin
So Meng Xiaoting isn't just
bahwa Xiao Ting bukan dirimu?
someone you've imagined?
Bagaimana dengan imajinasimu?
Would an imaginary person
Orang yang bisa dibayangkan,
have medical reports?
akan ada laporan pemeriksaan?
Chen Mo has left.
Chen Mo sudah keluar.
Meet at the studio
Jam 3 subuh.
at 3 a.m.
Sampai jumpa di studio.
Hello,
Halo.
who are you looking for?
Siapa yang kau cari?
There's a new swimming pool that just opened nearby.
Ada kolam renang baru di dekat sini.
Are you interested in swimming?
Apa kau butuh berenang?
Whether you exist or not
Kamu ada atau tidak,
isn't for Chen Mo to decide.
tidak bisa ditentukan oleh Chen Mo.
It's too dangerous for you to be alone, senior.
Kamu sendirian terlalu berbahaya, Senior.
Professor Chen.
Guru Chen.
Playing the piano by yourself?
Main piano sendiri?
Have a seat.
Duduk.
Unfortunately, I'm just a common person
Sayang sekali aku orang awam
with no taste for such refined pleasures.
tidak begitu tertarik.
Go ahead, ask.
Tanya saja.
Have you seen my wife?
Kau pernah bertemu istriku?
Yes,
Pernah.
but I don't know her.
Tidak kenal.
When did you see her?
Kapan pernah bertemu?
When I went to your house
Aku akan ke rumahmu.
looking for Meng Xiaoting.
Xiao Ting.
So what's your relationship
Apa hubunganmu
with Meng Xiaoting?
dengan Meng Xiao Ting?
She owes me money,
Dia berutang kepadaku.
I came to collect the debt.
Dia datang untuk menagih hutang.
You were looking for her and now me,
Kau mencarinya dan mencariku lagi?
just to collect a debt?
untuk menagih hutang?
Do I look like I'm lying?
Kau pikir aku berbohong?
No.
Tidak.
From the moment I saw you,
Saat pertama kali melihatmu,
I knew you were a smart person.
aku merasa kamu adalah orang yang pintar.
You clearly have a story.
Sekali lihat sudah tahu ada cerita.
Promising since childhood.
Sejak kecil sudah ada masa depan.
You look a lot like
Kamu mirip dengan
one of my younger brothers.
sangat mirip.
He really loved peanuts.
Dia sangat suka kacang.
In the past,
Dulu,
we used to harvest peanuts together.
kita pergi memetik kacang bersama.
We'd go barefoot,
Kita telanjang kaki.
stepping in the soil.
menginjak tanah.
The earth felt
Tanah.
cool against our skin.
yang dingin.
You'd pull out a string of peanuts.
Kamu mencabut serangkaian kacang.
Peanuts at that time
Kacang saat ini
were the tenderest and sweetest.
paling lembut dan manis.
You'd lie down on the peanut leaves.
Kamu berbaring di atas daun kacang.
Clouds floating in the sky.
Awan melayang di langit.
And you'd fall asleep.
Kau tertidur.
Are Meng Xiaoting and Li Meng
Xiao Ting dan Li Meng
the same person?
Apa mereka orang yang sama?
Yes.
Ya.
Did Meng Xiaoting come
Apakah Xiao Ting datang
to take revenge on Lin Yazhi?
untuk membalas dendam kepada Lin Ya Zhi?
Yes.
Ya.
Do you know Li Meng?
Apa kau kenal Li Meng?
When did you meet Li Meng?
Kapan kau mengenal Li Meng?
I've known her since childhood.
Sejak kecil.
When did you meet Chen Mo?
Kapan kamu mengenal Chen Mo?
A long time ago.
Sejak awal.
The power's out in this building,
gedung ini mati listrik.
they're closing up.
Sudah mau tutup.
Let's go!
Cepat pergi.
You're giving up on the money?
Tidak mau uang lagi?
Let me tell you,
Dengar.
I know about all the dirty things you've done,
Aku tahu semua perbuatan burukmu.
you'd better stay away from me.
Lebih baik kamu menjauh dariku.
Senior.
Senior.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Whatever you know,
Apa pun yang kau tahu,
keep your mouth shut,
Tutup mulutmu.
or I'll kill you.
Jika tidak, aku akan membunuhmu.
Tell me everything you know.
Katakan semua yang kamu tahu.
Miss Lin,
Nona Lin.
you've been hiding quite well.
Kau menyembunyikannya cukup dalam.
Talk and I'll call an ambulance for you.
Aku akan memanggil ambulans.
If you don't, I'll smash your head in. You believe me?
Jika tidak, aku akan memukulmu sampai mati.
Go ahead if you dare.
Kalau berani, pukul saja.
You think we don't dare?
Kau pikir kami tak berani?
If you die,
Jika kau mati,
Chen Mo will be the only suspect,
pembunuhnya hanya Chen Mo.
and we'll have nothing to do with it.
Tidak ada hubungannya dengan kita.
Do you still
Sekarang kamu masih
think we don't have the guts?
merasa kami tidak berani?
Li Meng is Meng Xiaoting's cousin.
Li Meng adalah sepupu Meng Xiao Ting.
It was Li Meng.
Itu Li Meng.
She arranged for Meng Xiaoting to stay by your side
Biarkan Meng Xiao Ting berada di sisimu.
so she could find a chance to kill you.
agar dia bisa membunuhmu.
How do you know that?
Bagaimana kau tahu?
Li Meng and I are from the same hometown,
Li Meng dan aku adalah teman sekampung.
I've helped her many times.
Aku banyak membantunya.
Meng Xiaoting's fake ID
KTP palsu Meng Xiao Ting
was arranged by me.
Aku yang membuatnya.
Go on.
Lanjutkan.
That's all.
Tidak ada lagi.
Finished?
Sudah selesai bicara?
Fine,
Baik.
Then I'll send you to meet your maker first.
Kalau begitu, aku akan mengantarmu menemui Raja Neraka dulu.
I'm telling you, this is all I know.
Aku bilang aku hanya tahu begitu banyak.
If that's all you know,
Jika kamu tahu begitu banyak,
then why would Chen Mo
Chen Mo,
kill to silence anyone?
membunuh orang?
Do you take us for fools?
Kau pikir kami bodoh?
Talk.
Katakan.
Seven years ago,
Tujuh tahun lalu,
Li Meng, in order to help Chen Mo.
Li Meng demi menyelamatkan Chen Mo,
She had just graduated then.
Saat itu dia baru lulus.
Are you pregnant?
Apa dia hamil?
Yes.
Ya.
Congratulations.
Selamat.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Honey,
Sayang.
I'm home.
Aku pulang.
You scared me.
Kau mengejutkanku.
I have a surprise.
Ada kejutan.
What surprise?
Kejutan apa?
Take a guess.
Coba tebak.
Did you find a new job?
Kau sudah menemukan pekerjaan baru?
Guess again.
Tebak lagi.
Then I have no idea.
Aku tidak bisa menebaknya.
I'm pregnant.
Aku hamil.
You don't like it?
Kau tidak suka?
No,
Tidak.
I do.
Suka.
This is our child.
Ini anak kita.
But right now
Tapi sekarang,
I don't even have a job.
bahkan tidak punya pekerjaan.
I'm just a broke student.
Hanya murid miskin.
Food, daily expenses,
Makan, minum, buang air besar.
and rent,
dan uang sewa.
it's all from
semuanya
your part-time jobs.
dari kerja paruh waktumu.
I can't even
Aku bahkan
afford the bride price to marry you.
bahkan tidak punya uang untuk menikahimu.
I don't want any bride price.
Aku tidak mau uang mahar.
As long as you're willing,
Asalkan kau bersedia,
we can get our marriage license tomorrow.
besok kita pergi mengambil surat nikah.
You really don't mind that I'm poor?
Kau sungguh tak merasa aku miskin?
Just focus on your doctoral exam at home.
Kau bisa belajar di rumah.
Once you get your PhD and make good money,
Setelah kau lulus ujian dan menghasilkan banyak uang,
I'm counting on you
kelak masih berharap
to buy formula for our baby.
membelikan susu formula untuk anak.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
There's actually quite a big gap between people.
Sebenarnya perbedaan antara orang cukup besar.
I went for a check-up today
Aku akan memeriksanya hari ini.
and met this young lady
Aku bertemu gadis itu.
who became a doctor right after graduation.
Baru lulus sudah menjadi dokter.
She's beautiful,
Orangnya juga baik,
comes from a wealthy family,
Keluarganya juga baik.
a typical rich pretty girl,
tipikal wanita kaya dan cantik.
and still single.
Masih lajang.
I can manage by myself.
Aku bisa sendiri.
You're studying psychology?
Kau belajar psikologi?
I'm preparing for my doctorate.
sedang ujian S2.
But compared to being a psychologist,
Tapi dibandingkan psikolog,
I'd rather be a pianist.
aku lebih bersedia menjadi pianis.
A pianist?
Pianis?
She said she wants someone tall,
Dia bilang dia ingin mencari yang tinggi.
slim,
kurus.
refined,
Sangat lembut.
preferably wearing glasses,
Lebih baik memakai kacamata.
and involved in the arts.
atau membuat seni?
Because pianos, like psychologists,
Karena piano sama seperti psikiater,
both have the power to move people's hearts.
memiliki kekuatan untuk menggetarkan hati orang.
You're
Kau...
also from the medical department.
Kau juga dari Departemen Kedokteran?
How did you know?
Bagaimana kau tahu?
I...
Aku...
You smell
Di tubuhmu
like hospital antiseptic.
bau obat rumah sakit.
Is it that obvious?
Begitu jelas?
Maybe I just have a sensitive nose.
Mungkin indra penciumanku lebih tajam.
I've been strange since childhood,
Sejak kecil aku sangat aneh.
I don't care for perfumes,
tidak suka parfum.
but I love
Aku suka.
the smell of hospital antiseptic.
bau obat rumah sakit.
You are quite strange indeed.
Kau memang aneh.
I'm an OB-GYN.
Aku dokter kandungan.
Wow,
Wah.
that's impressive!
Hebat sekali.
So young and already a doctor.
Kau menjadi dokter di usia semuda ini?
You're impressive too,
Kau juga hebat.
about to take your doctoral exams.
Sebentar lagi ujian masuk perguruan tinggi.
Good luck.
Semangat.
Tonight at six,
Pukul 18.00.
Sure.
Baiklah.
would you like to have dinner together?
Mau makan bersama?
Okay.
Boleh.
What food do you like?
Kau suka makan apa?
My treat.
Aku traktir.